What do you think of when I say the word "design"?
بماذا تفكرون حين أقول كلمة "تصميم"؟
You probably think of things like this,
تقريبًا تفكرون في أشياء مثل هذه،
finely crafted objects that you can hold in your hand,
المنتجات النهائية التي يمكنكم حملها في يديكم،
or maybe logos and posters and maps
أو ربما الشعارات والملصقات والخرائط
that visually explain things,
التي توضح الأشياء بصريًا
classic icons of timeless design.
الأيقونات التقليدية في التصميم الثابت.
But I'm not here to talk about that kind of design.
لكني لم آت إلى هنا للحديث عن ذلك النوع من التصميمات.
I want to talk about the kind
أريد التحدث عن النوع
that you probably use every day
الذي تستخدمونه كل يوم تقريبًا
and may not give much thought to,
وربما لا تولنه اهتمامًا كبيرًا،
designs that change all the time
التصميمات التي تتغير طوال الوقت
and that live inside your pocket.
وتلك التي تعيش داخل جيبكم.
I'm talking about the design
أتحدث عن تصميم
of digital experiences
التجارب الرقمية
and specifically the design of systems
وخاصةً تصميم الأنظمة
that are so big that their scale
الكبيرة جدًا بحيث قد يكون من الصعب
can be hard to comprehend.
استيعاب نطاقها.
Consider the fact that Google processes
بالنظر في حقيقة أن جوجل تتعامل مع
over one billion search queries every day,
أكثر من مليار عملية بحث كل يوم،
that every minute, over 100 hours
وأنه في كل دقيقة، أكثر من 100 ساعة
of footage are uploaded to YouTube.
من اللقطات ترفع على اليوتيوب.
That's more in a single day
وذلك، في يوم واحد، أكثر
than all three major U.S. networks broadcast
من كل ما تم بثه من الثلاث شبكات الأمريكية الرئيسية
in the last five years combined.
في الخمس سنوات الماضية مجتمعة.
And Facebook transmitting the photos,
ويرسل الفيسبوك الصور،
messages and stories
والرسائل، والقصص
of over 1.23 billion people.
من أكثر من 1,23 مليار شخص.
That's almost half of the Internet population,
ذلك حوالي نصف مستخدمي الإنترنت،
and a sixth of humanity.
وسُدس البشرية.
These are some of the products
هذه بعض المنتجات
that I've helped design over the course of my career,
التي ساعدت في تصميمها على مدار مسيرتي المهنية،
and their scale is so massive
ونطاقها هائل جدًا
that they've produced unprecedented
حيث أنتجت
design challenges.
تحديات تصميم غير مسبوقة.
But what is really hard
لكن ما هو صعب حقًا
about designing at scale is this:
في التصميم على نطاق واسع هو أنه:
It's hard in part because
صعب جزئيًا لأنه
it requires a combination of two things,
يتطلب الجمع بين شيئين
audacity and humility —
الجرأة والتواضع ــــ
audacity to believe that the thing that you're making
الجرأة لتؤمن أن الشيء الذي تقوم بصنعه
is something that the entire world wants and needs,
هو الشيء الذي يريده ويحتاجه العالم بأسره،
and humility to understand that as a designer,
والتواضع لتستوعب كمصمم،
it's not about you or your portfolio,
أن هذا ليس لنفسك أو لمحفظتك،
it's about the people that you're designing for,
بل هذا للناس الذين تصمم لهم،
and how your work just might help them
وكيف يمكن أن يساعدهم عملك
live better lives.
ليعيشوا حياة أفضل.
Now, unfortunately, there's no school
الآن، لسوء الحظ، لا توجد مدرسة
that offers the course Designing for Humanity 101.
توفر دورات مبادئ التصميم للبشرية.
I and the other designers
أنا والمصممون الآخرون
who work on these kinds of products
الذين يعملون في مثل هذه المنتجات
have had to invent it as we go along,
كان علينا اختراعه ونحن نمضي قدمًا،
and we are teaching ourselves
ونعلم أنفسنا
the emerging best practices
أفضل التطبيقات الناشئة
of designing at scale,
للتصميم على نطاق واسع،
and today I'd like share some of the things
واليوم أود أن أشارككم بعضا من الأشياء
that we've learned over the years.
التي تعلمناها عبر السنين.
Now, the first thing that you need to know
الآن، أول شيء أنتم بحاجة
about designing at scale
لمعرفته عن التصميم
is that the little things really matter.
على نطاق واسع هي الأشياء الصغيرة التي حقًا تهم.
Here's a really good example of how
هنا مثال جيد فعلًا عن كيف
a very tiny design element can make a big impact.
يستطيع عنصر تصميم صغير جدًا أن يُحدث تأثيرا كبيرا.
The team at Facebook that manages
فريق الفيسبوك الذي يدير
the Facebook "Like" button
زر "أعجبني" في الفيسبوك
decided that it needed to be redesigned.
قرروا أنه بحاجة لإعادة التصميم.
The button had kind of gotten out of sync
حدث للزر نوع من الخروج عن التزامن
with the evolution of our brand
مع التطور لعلامتنا التجارية
and it needed to be modernized.
وهو بحاجة للتحديث.
Now you might think, well, it's a tiny little button,
قد تفكرون الآن، أنه زر صغير للغاية،
it probably is a pretty straightforward,
إنه واضح بشدة،
easy design assignment, but it wasn't.
مهمة تصميم سهلة، لكنها لم تكن كذلك.
Turns out, there were all kinds of constraints
تبين، أنه كان هناك كل أنواع القيود
for the design of this button.
لتصميم هذا الزر.
You had to work within specific height and width parameters.
عليك أن تعمل في حدود معاملات طول وعرض محددة.
You had to be careful to make it work
عليك الحذر لجعله يعمل
in a bunch of different languages,
في حزمة من اللغات المختلفة،
and be careful about using fancy gradients or borders
وتوخي الحذر في استخدام التدرجات والحدود الوهمية
because it has to degrade gracefully
لأنه يجب أن يتدرج بلطف
in old web browsers.
في متصفحات الويب القديمة.
The truth is, designing this tiny little button
الحقيقة هي، أن تصميم هذا الزر الصغير للغاية
was a huge pain in the butt.
كان معاناة كبيرة.
Now, this is the new version of the button,
الآن، هذا هو الإصدار الجديد للزر،
and the designer who led this project estimates
والمصمم الذي قاد هذا المشروع يقدر
that he spent over 280 hours
أنه قضى أكثر من 280 ساعة
redesigning this button over the course of months.
ليعيد تصميم هذا الزر على مدى شهور.
Now, why would we spend so much time
الآن، لماذا نقضي وقت طويل جدًا
on something so small?
في شيء صغير جدًا؟
It's because when you're designing at scale,
هذا لأنه حين تصمم على نطاق واسع،
there's no such thing as a small detail.
ليس هناك شيء كالتفاصيل الصغيرة.
This innocent little button
هذا الزر الصغير البريء
is seen on average 22 billion times a day
تتم مشاهدته 22 مليار مرة في اليوم
and on over 7.5 million websites.
وعلى أكثر من 7,5 مليون موقع.
It's one of the single most viewed design elements ever created.
إنه أحد العناصر الأكثر مشاهدةً التي تم تصميمها على الإطلاق.
Now that's a lot of pressure for a little button
الآن هذا كثير من الضغط على الزر الصغير
and the designer behind it,
والمصمم الذي خلفه،
but with these kinds of products,
لكن مع هذه الأنواع من المنتجات،
you need to get even the tiny things right.
تحتاج لتحصل عليها صحيحة حتى إن كانت صغيرة.
Now, the next thing that you need to understand
الآن، الشيء التالي الذي عليك استيعابه
is how to design with data.
هو كيف تصمم مع البيانات.
Now, when you're working on products like this,
الآن، حين تعمل على منتجات مثل هذه،
you have incredible amounts of information
لديك كم هائل من المعلومات
about how people are using your product
عن مدى استخدام الناس لمنتجك
that you can then use to influence
حيث يمكنك من ثم استخدامها للتأثير
your design decisions,
على قرارات تصميمك،
but it's not just as simple as following the numbers.
لكنها ليست ببساطة مجرد اتباع الأرقام.
Let me give you an example
دعوني أعطيكم مثالا
so that you can understand what I mean.
لتفهموا ما أعنيه.
Facebook has had a tool for a long time
امتلك فيسبوك لوقت طويل أداة
that allowed people to report photos
تسمح للناس بالإبلاغ عن الصور
that may be in violation of our community standards,
التي ربما تنتهك معايرنا المجتمعية،
things like spam and abuse.
أشياء مثل البريد المزعج وسوء الاستخدام.
And there were a ton of photos reported,
وكان هناك طن من الصور تم الإبلاغ عنها،
but as it turns out,
لكن كما اتضح،
only a small percentage were actually
فقط نسبة صغيرة كانت فعلا
in violation of those community standards.
تنتهك معايرهم المجتمعية.
Most of them were just your typical party photo.
معظمهم كان مجرد صور من حفلات عادية.
Now, to give you a specific hypothetical example,
الآن، لأعطيكم مثال افتراضي معين،
let's say my friend Laura hypothetically
دعوني أقول صديقتي لورا ترفع افتراضيًا
uploads a picture of me
صورة لي
from a drunken night of karaoke.
سكرانة في حفلة كاريكوكي ليلًا.
This is purely hypothetical, I can assure you.
هذا افتراضي بحت، أستطيع أن أؤكد لكم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, incidentally,
الآن، بالمناسبة،
you know how some people are kind of worried
هل تعرف كيف أن بعض الناس
that their boss or employee
قلقون من أن رئيسهم أو موظفيهم
is going to discover embarrassing photos of them
سوف يكتشفون صورة محرجة لهم
on Facebook?
على الفيسبوك؟
Do you know how hard that is to avoid
هل تعرف ما صعوبة تجنب هذا
when you actually work at Facebook?
حين تكونون تعملون في فيسبوك فعلًا؟
So anyway, there are lots of these photos
على أي حال، هناك الكثير من الصور
being erroneously reported as spam and abuse,
يتم الإبلاغ عنها خطأ كبريد مزعج أو سوء استخدام،
and one of the engineers on the team had a hunch.
وواحد من مهندسي الفريق لديه حدس.
He really thought there was something else going on
اعتقد أن هناك حقًا شيءٌ ما آخر يجري
and he was right,
وكان على حق،
because when he looked through a bunch of the cases,
لأنه حين نظر خلال مجموعة من الحالات،
he found that most of them
وجد أن معظمها
were from people who were requesting
كانوا من الناس الذين قاموا بطلب
the takedown of a photo of themselves.
إزالة صورة لأنفسهم.
Now this was a scenario that the team
وكان هذا هو السيناريو الذي لم يوضع
never even took into account before.
حتى في اعتبار الفريق أبدًا من قبل.
So they added a new feature
لذلك وضعوا خاصية جديدة
that allowed people to message their friend
تسمح للناس بمراسلة أصدقائهم
to ask them to take the photo down.
ليطلبوا منهم إزالة الصورة.
But it didn't work.
لكن هذا لم يعمل.
Only 20 percent of people
فقط 20 بالمائة من الناس
sent the message to their friend.
أرسلوا رسالة لأصدقائهم.
So the team went back at it.
لذلك تراجع عنها الفريق.
They consulted with experts in conflict resolution.
قاموا باستشارة خبراء في حل النزاع.
They even studied the universal principles
قاموا حتى بدراسة المبادئ العالمية
of polite language,
للغة مهذبة،
which I didn't even actually know existed
التي لم أكن أعرف عن وجودها فعلًا
until this research happened.
حتى حدث هذا البحث.
And they found something really interesting.
ووجدوا شيئا شيقًا حقًا.
They had to go beyond just helping people
كان عليهم أن يذهبوا إلى ما وراء مجرد مساعدة
ask their friend to take the photo down.
الناس ليطلبوا من أصدقائهم إزالة الصورة.
They had to help people express to their friend
كان عليهم مساعدة الناس للتعبير لأصدقئهم
how the photo made them feel.
كيف جعلتهم الصورة يشعرون.
Here's how the experience works today.
هنا كيف يشتغل الأمر اليوم.
So I find this hypothetical photo of myself,
أجد هذه الصورة الافتراضية لنفسي،
and it's not spam, it's not abuse,
وهي ليست بريدا مزعجا، وليست سوء استخدام،
but I really wish it weren't on the site.
ولكني أتمنى حقًا لو لم تكن على الموقع.
So I report it and I say,
لذلك أبلغت عنها وقلت،
"I'm in this photo and I don't like it,"
"أنا في هذه الصورة وإنها لا تعجبني"
and then we dig deeper.
ثم بحثنا أعمق.
Why don't you like this photo of yourself?
لماذا لا تعجبك صورتك هذه؟
And I select "It's embarrassing."
واخترت "إنها تسبب لي الإحراج."
And then I'm encouraged to message my friend,
ثم تم تحفيزي لأُراسل صديقي،
but here's the critical difference.
لكن هنا الفرق الحاسم.
I'm provided specific suggested language
قُدمت لي لغة مقترحة خاصة
that helps me communicate to Laura
تساعدني على التواصل مع لورا
how the photo makes me feel.
كيف تجعلني الصورة أشعر.
Now the team found that this relatively small change
الآن وجد الفريق أن هذا التغير الصغير نسبيًا
had a huge impact.
أحدث تأثيرًا ضخمًا.
Before, only 20 percent of people
من قبل، فقط 20 بالمائة من الناس
were sending the message,
أرسلوا الرسالة.
and now 60 percent were,
والآن 60 بالمائة أرسلوا،
and surveys showed that people
وقد أظهرت الاستقصاءات أن الناس
on both sides of the conversation
على جانبي المحادثة
felt better as a result.
شعروا بتحسن نتيجة لذلك.
That same survey showed
هذا الاستقصاء نفسه أظهر
that 90 percent of your friends
أن 90 بالمائة من أصدقائكم
want to know if they've done something to upset you.
يريدون أن يعرفوا إن كانوا قد قاموا بشيء أزعجكم.
Now I don't know who the other 10 percent are,
الآن لا أعلم من يكون ال 10 بالمائة الآخرين
but maybe that's where our "Unfriend" feature
لكن قد ربما قد يكون استخداما جيدا
can come in handy.
لخاصيتنا في "إلغاء الصداقة".
So as you can see,
إذًا كما ترون الآن،
these decisions are highly nuanced.
تلك القرارات ذات فوارق دقيقة للغاية.
Of course we use a lot of data
بالطبع نستخدم الكثير من البيانات
to inform our decisions,
لنعزز قراراتنا،
but we also rely very heavily on iteration,
لكننا أيضًا نعتمد بشدة على التكرار،
research, testing, intuition, human empathy.
والبحث والاختبار والبديهة، والتواصل الحسي البشري.
It's both art and science.
إنها كل من الفن والعلم.
Now, sometimes the designers who work on these products
الآن، المصممون الذين يعملون على هذه المنتجات أحيانًا
are called "data-driven,"
يطلق عليهم "المدفوعون بالبيانات"
which is a term that totally drives us bonkers.
المصطلح الذي يدفعنا تمامًا للجنون.
The fact is, it would be irresponsible of us
الحقيقة هي، يعد الأمر انعدام مسئولية من طرفنا
not to rigorously test our designs
إن لم نختبر تصميماتنا بصرامة
when so many people are counting on us
حين يعول علينا الكثير جدًا من الناس
to get it right,
للحصول عليها بشكل صحيح،
but data analytics
لكن تحليلات البيانات
will never be a substitute for design intuition.
لن تكون أبدًا بديلًا عن بديهية التصميم.
Data can help you make a good design great,
تستطيع البيانات أن تساعدكم لجعل تصميم جيد عظيمًا،
but it will never made a bad design good.
لكنها لن تجعل أبدًا تصميما سيء جيدًا.
The next thing that you need to understand as a principle
الشيء التالي الذي عليك استيعابه كمبدأ
is that when you introduce change,
هو متى تقوم بإدخال تغيير،
you need to do it extraordinarily carefully.
أنت بحاجة لتقوم به بشكل غير عادي بعناية.
Now I often have joked that
الآن كثيرًا ما أقول مازحة
I spend almost as much time
بأنني أقضي وقتا أطول
designing the introduction of change
في تصميم مقدمة التغيير
as I do the change itself,
مما أفعل في التغيير نفسه،
and I'm sure that we can all relate to that
وأنا متأكدة أننا جميعًا يمكن أن نرتبط بذلك
when something that we use a lot changes
حين نستخدم الكثير من التغيرات بشيء ما
and then we have to adjust.
ومن ثم يجب علينا أن نُعدله.
The fact is, people can become
الحقيقة هي، يمكن أن يصبح الناس
very efficient at using bad design,
فعالين جدًا في استخدام تصميم سيء،
and so even if the change is good for them in the long run,
وكذلك حتى لو كان التغيير جيدا لهم على المدى البعيد،
it's still incredibly frustrating when it happens,
لا يزال هذا محبطًا بصورة لا تصدق حين يحدث،
and this is particularly true
وهذا صحيح بشكل خاص
with user-generated content platforms,
مع منصات المحتوى المقدم من المستخدمين،
because people can rightfully claim a sense of ownership.
لأن الناس يستطيعون، ومن حقهم، المطالبة بحق الملكية.
It is, after all, their content.
هذا هو، بعد كل شيء، محتواهم.
Now, years ago, when I was working at YouTube,
الآن، منذ سنين، حين كنت أعمل باليوتيوب،
we were looking for ways to
كنا نبحث عن طرق
encourage more people to rate videos,
لتحفيز ناس أكثر على تقييم الفيديوهات،
and it was interesting because when we looked into the data,
وكان هذا شيقا لأنه حين تفحصنا البيانات،
we found that almost everyone was exclusively using
وجدنا أنه في الغالب كان كل شخص يستخدم بصورة حصرية
the highest five-star rating,
أعلى تقييم خمس نجوم،
a handful of people were using
وحفنة من الناس كانوا يستخدمون
the lowest one-star,
أقل تقييم نجمة واحدة،
and virtually no one
وتقريبًا ولا واحد
was using two, three or four stars.
كان يستخدم نجمتان أو ثلاث أو أربع نجمات.
So we decided to simplify
لذلك قررنا التبسيط
into an up-down kind of voting binary model.
لنوع فوق أو تحت في نموذج تصويت ثنائي.
It's going to be much easier for people to engage with.
سيكون هذا أسهل للناس في التعامل معه.
But people were very attached
لكن الناس كانوا مرتبطين جدًا
to the five-star rating system.
بنظام الخمس نجوم للتقييم.
Video creators really loved their ratings.
أَحَبَ مبدعون الفيديو تقييماتهم حقًا.
Millions and millions of people
ملايين وملايين من الناس
were accustomed to the old design.
كانوا معتادون على التصميم القديم.
So in order to help people
لذلك من أجل مساعدة الناس
prepare themselves for change
لتجهيز أنفسهم للتغيير
and acclimate to the new design more quickly,
والتأقلم أسرع مع التصميم الحديث،
we actually published the data graph
في الواقع نشرنا الرسم البياني للبيانات
sharing with the community
لنشارك المجتمع
the rationale for what we were going to do,
الأسباب المنطقية لما نحن بصدد القيام به،
and it even engaged the larger industry
شاركوا حتى في الصناعة الأكبر
in a conversation, which resulted in
في محادثة، التي أدت إلى
my favorite TechCrunch headline of all time:
عنوان تك كرانش الرئيسي لكل العصور المفضل لدي:
"YouTube Comes to a 5-Star Realization:
"وصل اليوتيوب إلى إدراك برتبة الـ5 نجوم:
Its Ratings Are Useless."
تقيماته عديمة الفائدة"
Now, it's impossible to completely avoid
الآن، من المستحيل أن تتجنب تمامًا
change aversion when you're making changes
النفور من التغيير حين تجري تغييرات
to products that so many people use.
لمنتجات يستخدمها كثير جدًا من الناس.
Even though we tried to do all the right things,
على الرغم من أننا حاولنا
we still received our customary flood
فعل الأشياء الصحيحة لا نزال نستقبل
of video protests and angry emails
الفيضان المعتاد من فيديو الاحتجاجات والرسائل الغاضبة.
and even a package that had to be scanned by security,
وحتى الحزم التي وجب فحصها من طرف الأمن،
but we have to remember
لكن علينا أن نتذكر
people care intensely about this stuff,
أن الناس مهتمون بشدة بتلك الأشياء،
and it's because these products, this work,
وهذا لأن تلك المنتجات، هذا العمل،
really, really matters to them.
مهم حقًا بالنسبة لهم.
Now, we know that we have to be careful
الآن، نحن نعلم أنه يجب علينا توخي الحذر
about paying attention to the details,
حول الالتفات إلى التفاصيل،
we have to be cognizant about how we use data
يجب علينا أن نكون مدركين لكيفية استخدام البيانات
in our design process,
في إجراء تصميمنا،
and we have to introduce change
وعلينا أن ندخل التغيير
very, very carefully.
بحذر بالغ.
Now, these things are all really useful.
الآن، تلك الأشياء كلها مفيدة حقًا.
They're good best practices for designing at scale.
هذه أجود التطبيقات للتصميم واسع النطاق.
But they don't mean anything
لكنها لا تعني شيئًا
if you don't understand something
إن لم تستوعب شيئًا
much more fundamental.
أكثر جوهرية من ذلك.
You have to understand who you are designing for.
عليك أن تستوعب من الذين تصمم لهم.
Now, when you set a goal to design
الآن، حين تضع هدف لتصميم
for the entire human race,
للجنس البشري بأسره،
and you start to engage in that goal in earnest,
وتبدأ في الدخول في هذا الهدف بشكل جدي،
at some point you run into the walls
في نقطة ما تواجه جدار
of the bubble that you're living in.
الفقاعة التي تعيش داخلها.
Now, in San Francisco, we get a little miffed
الآن، في سان فرانسسكو، نغضب قليلًا
when we hit a dead cell zone
حين نصادف منطقة خارج التغطية
because we can't use our phones to navigate
لأننا لا نستطيع استخدام هواتفنا
to the new hipster coffee shop.
لننتقل إلى محل القهوة الجديد.
But what if you had to drive four hours
لكن ماذا لو كان عليك القيادة لأربع ساعات
to charge your phone
لشحن هاتفك
because you had no reliable source of electricity?
لأنه ليس لديك مصدر معتمد للكهرباء؟
What if you had no access to public libraries?
ماذا لو لم تكن تستطيع الولوج للمكتبات العامة؟
What if your country had no free press?
ماذا لو أن بلدك ليس لديها صحافة حرة؟
What would these products start to mean to you?
ماذا كانت تلك المنتجات لتعني لك؟
This is what Google, YouTube and Facebook
هكذا يبدو جوجل ويوتيوب وفيسبوك
look like to most of the world,
لمعظم العالم،
and it's what they'll look like
وهي ما ستبدوا عليه
to most of the next five billion people
لمعظم الخمسة مليار شخص الذين
to come online.
سيتصلون بالإنترنيت لاحقا.
Designing for low-end cell phones
التصميم للهواتف المحمولة المتدنية
is not glamorous design work,
ليس بعمل تصميم براق،
but if you want to design for the whole world,
لكن إن أردت أن تصمم للعالم أجمع،
you have to design for where people are,
عليك أن تصمم لحيث يكون الناس،
and not where you are.
وليس لحيث تكون أنت.
So how do we keep this big, big picture in mind?
إذًا كيف نبقي على تلك الصورة الكبيرة في أذهاننا؟
We try to travel outside of our bubble to see, hear
نحاول السفر خارج فقاعتنا لنرى، ونسمع
and understand the people we're designing for.
ونفهم الناس الذين نصمم من أجلهم.
We use our products in non-English languages
نستخدم منتجاتنا بلغات غير إنجليزية
to make sure that they work just as well.
لنتأكد أنها تعمل جيدًا
And we try to use one of these phones from time to time
ونحاول أن نستخدم واحد من تلك الهواتف من حين لآخر
to keep in touch with their reality.
لنتواصل مع واقعهم.
So what does it mean to design at a global scale?
إذًا ماذا يعني التصميم على نطاق عالمي؟
It means difficult and sometimes exasperating work
يعني عملا صعبا وأحيانًا مستفزا
to try to improve and evolve products.
لتحاول تحسين وتطوير المنتجات.
Finding the audacity and the humility to do right by them
إيجاد الجرأة والتواضع لتقوم بما يصلح.
can be pretty exhausting,
يمكن أن يكون مرهقا جدًا،
and the humility part,
والتواضع جزء،
it's a little tough on the design ego.
قاس قليلًا على غرور التصميم.
Because these products are always changing,
لأن تلك المنتجات تتغير دائمًا،
everything that I've designed in my career
كل شيء قد قمت بتصميمه في حياتي المهنية
is pretty much gone,
اختفى إلى حد كبير،
and everything that I will design will fade away.
وكل شيء سوف أقوم بتصميمه سوف يفنى.
But here's what remains:
لكن ما يبقى:
the never-ending thrill
اللذة اللانهائية
of being a part of something that is so big,
لكونك جزء من شيء كبير جدًا،
you can hardly get your head around it,
يمكن بالكاد أن تلف رأسك من حوله،
and the promise that it just might change the world.
واحتمال أنه قد يغير العالم حقًا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)